Guide to the Blanche Matthias Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1917-50; Series IV; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  - PLACES
    - Istanbul, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 193)
    - Italy: postcards, 1930, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 194)
    - Jakarta: postcards, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 195)
    - Java, 1919 Sep (Box 11, Folder 196)
    - Jerusalem and Holy Land (Box 11, Folder 197)
    - Korea, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 198)
    - Mountains, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 199)
    - Orient, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 200)
    - Rhodes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - Spain: postcards, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - Syria, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 203)
    - United States: postcards, 1929, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - World tour, 1919-20 (Box 12, Folder 205)
  - PEOPLE AND OBJECTS
    - Clapp, Frederick Mortimer, 1949-50, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - Dale, James, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - Faggi, Alfeo: sculpture by, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - Forbes, M. D., 1922, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - Katchamakoff, A.: photograph by, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - Larson, Marie C., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - Matisse, Peter, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - Matthias, Blanche: sculpture by A. Katchamakoff, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - Ufer, Walter, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 214)
- Family Papers, 1901-61; Series V; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Family Papers are alphabetically arranged by subject.
  - Business cards: Russell J. Matthias, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 215)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 216-17)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 218-28)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 229-40)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1921-25 (Box 13, Folder 241)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 242)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 243)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1930-31 (Box 13, Folder 244)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 245)
  - Correspondence, Travel, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 246)
  - Correspondence, 1960, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 247)
  - Diaries
    - Japan, China, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 248)
    - Philippines, China, Korea, Japan, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 249)
    - World tour: excerpts from letters by Blanche Matthias, 1919-20 (Box 14, Folder 250)
    - Central Europe, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 251)
    - British Isles, Netherlands, France, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 252)
  - Illustrated cards
    - Advertising cards, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 253-55)
    - Greeting cards, 1901, 1957, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 256)
    - Other: children, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 257-58)
    - Other: comic, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 259-60)
    - Other: miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 261)
  - International drivers licenses, 1937, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 262)
  - Medical bill, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 263)
  - Memorabilia
    - Japan, China, 1917, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 264)
    - World tour, 1918-20, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 265-66)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1937, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 267)
  - Passports
    - Coates, Victoria S., 1928 (Box 15, Folder 268)
    - Matthias, Blanche Coates, 1919-25 (Box 15, Folder 269)
    - Matthias, Russell J., 1917-37 (Box 15, Folder 270-72)
  - Printed material
    See also: Oversize, Box 16, folders 291-92
    - Clapp, Frederick Mortimer, review of The Drawings of the Venetian Painters in the 15th and 16th Centuries, by Hans Tietze and E. Tietze-Conrat, in The Art Bulletin, 1945 Jun (Box 15, Folder 273)
    - Hart, George: catalog of paintings, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 274)
    - d'Orage, Jeanne, A Single Poem, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 275)
    - Peabody Museum Oceanographic and Ornithological Laboratories (Box 15, Folder 276)
    - Prospectus, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 277)
    - Siedle, Louis, 56 Years in Ceylon, 1872-1928, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 278)
  - Sea travel
    - Passenger lists, 1913-38 (Box 15, Folder 279-81)
    - Passenger ticket, First class, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 282)
    - R.M.S. Aquitania: brochure, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 283)
  - "Tantine", 1928-39, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 284)
  - transition, 1928, 1952, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 285)
- Oversize, 1922-82; 2; (1 box)
  Oversize holds materials from Series II, III, and V and the papers are arranged in series order.
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1965-82, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 286-87)
    - Sweeney, James Johnson, 1941, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 288)
    - Thurman, Howard, 1978 Feb (Box 16, Folder 289)
  - WRITINGS
    - Scrapbook, 1922-31 (Box 16, Folder 290)
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - Indian and Eastern Motors, 1922 Oct (Box 16, Folder 291)
    - Turbyfill, Mark, "Begging the Chicago Poet," The Chicagoan, 1932 Mar (Box 16, Folder 292)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted Fragile Papers in Box 17 may only be consulted with the permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
  - Box 1, folder 1 (Box 17, Folder 293)
  - Box 1, folder 12 (Box 17, Folder 294)
  - Box 1, folder 31 (Box 17, Folder 295)
  - Box 2, folder 55 (Box 17, Folder 296)
  - Box 2, folder 71 (Box 17, Folder 297)
  - Box 3, folder 87 (Box 17, Folder 298)
  - Box 3, folder 99 (Box 17, Folder 299)
  - Box 4, folder 122 (Box 17, Folder 300)
  - Box 4, folder 123 (Box 17, Folder 301)
  - Box 4, folder 125 (Box 17, Folder 302)
  - Box 4, folder 126 (Box 17, Folder 303)
  - Box 4, folder 127 (Box 17, Folder 304)
  - Box 4, folders 129-31 (Box 17, Folder 305)
  - Box 4, folder 134 (Box 17, Folder 306)
  - Box 4, folder 139 (Box 17, Folder 307)
  - Box 4, folder 140 (Box 17, Folder 308)
  - Box 4, folder 141 (Box 17, Folder 309)
  - Box 4, folder 142 (Box 17, Folder 310)
  - Box 4, folder 144 (Box 17, Folder 311)
  - Box 5, folder 147 (Box 17, Folder 312)
  - Box 5, folder 148 (Box 17, Folder 313)
  - Box 5, folder 150 (Box 17, Folder 314)
  - Box 5, folder 151 (Box 17, Folder 315)
  - Box 5, folder 152 (Box 17, Folder 316)
  - Box 5, folder 154 (Box 17, Folder 317)
  - Box 13, folder 218 (Box 17, Folder 318)
  - Box 14, folder 248 (Box 17, Folder 319)
  - Box 16, folder 286 (Box 17, Folder 320)
  - Box 16, folder 287 (Box 17, Folder 321)
  - Box 16, folder 288 (Box 17, Folder 322)